Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- Carte de l'Ile de Madagascar dite aujourd'hui i'Ile Daufine. = Map of the island of Madagascar called Dauphine Island. -- Amsterdam: Chatelain, Henri Abraham; Chatelain, Henri Abraham, 1719; NOR 0337; : Colored; 36 cm. x 43.5 cm.
  RID: MOA 0121
  Islands -- Madagascar -- 18th c.
- Particular draughts of some of the chief African Islands in the Mediterranean, as also in the Atlantic and Ethiopic Oceans. -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1752; NOR 0338; : Uncolored; 34.5 cm. x 43 cm.
  Source: Complete System of Geography (1752)
  Descriptive Notes: This map also appeared in Complete Atlas (1752). Consists of seven maps. 'An accurate map of the islands of Malta, Goza and Cuming'; An accurate chart of of Cape Verde Islands'; 'The Bay of Agoa de Saldanha'; 'Island of Teneriffe'; Plan of the Dutch Fort at the Cape of Good Hope'; 'A draught of Table Bay'; Island of Madera'; A correct map of the Island of St. Hellena, belonging to the English East Company.'
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0338, p. 387
  Norwich number: 0338
  RID: MOA 0107
  Islands -- African islands -- 18th c.
- Carte Reduite du Canal de Mozambique et des Isles de Madagascar, de France, de Bourbon, de Rodriques et autres. = Sea chart of the Mozambique channel and the Islands of Madagascar, France, Bourbon and Rodrigues. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772 Sea chart, 1767; NOR 0339; : Colored; 59 cm. x 87 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes the Islands of Madagascar, France, Bourbon (Reunion) and Rodriques. Inset: two plans of the port of Seychelles and the Island of Assumption. Sea contains numerous rhumb lines; Prime meridian through Paris.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0339, p. 388
  Norwich number: 0339
  RID: MOA 0092
  Islands -- Mozambique Channel -- 18th c.
- Plan de la Forteresse et Bourg, de l'Isle de Ste. Helene. = Plan of the fort and town on St. Helena. -- Unknown: Anonymous; Anonymous, No date; NOR 0340; : Outline color; 22 cm. x 17 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Top right: Tome 3. No. 124.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0340, p. 389
  Norwich number: 0340
  RID: MOA 0245
  Islands -- St. Helene -- Unknown
- Plan of Cape Town, Cape of Good Hope. -- London: Day Son; Day, John and Son, 1854; NOR 0343; : Uncolored; 31.5 cm. x 39.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map also appears in A. H. Honikman's book: Cape Town, City of Good Hope (1966). Includes "forty-four numbered references to places existing at that time in the town and its surroundings. "
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0343, p. 392
  Norwich number: 0343
  RID: MOA 0136
  Africa -- Cape Town -- 19th c.
- Africa. South-east coast. East London harbour and approaches. Surveyed by ... -- London: Richards, G. H. (George Henry); Archdeacon, W.E.; Crabtree, W.R.; Archdeacon, W.E.; Crabtree, W.R. Sea chart, 1869; NOR 0344; : Uncolored; 65.5 cm. x 48.4 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First published in 1869, revised editions appeared in 1889, 1898, 1901 and 1912. Landmarks around the harbour are illustrated with a relief map. Insets: East London harbour and Elevation of coastline.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0344, p. 393
  Norwich number: 0344
  RID: MOA 0306
  Oceans -- Sea chart -- 19th c.
- Plan van de geproclameerde Goud Velden te Witwatersrand, Z.A.R. = Plan of the proclaimed gold-fields at the Witwatersrand. -- Pretoria: Landmeter Generaal's Kantoor; Rissik, Johann F.B., 1857-1925, 1886; NOR 0345; : Uncolored; 12 cm. x 23.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Photocopy. "This diagram is of great historical importance, as it is believed to be the first diagram depicting the location of the village of Johannesburg on government ground, and the first diagram showing the location of Mynpachts, mining right leases on Witwatersrand gold fields ... ". Inset: Lyst van Mynpachten Toegestaan.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0345, p. 394
  Norwich number: 0345
  RID: MOA 0310
  Africa -- Surveyor's plan -- 19th c.
- Cape of Good Hope. --: Millar Hogg, NOR 1000; :; x
  Descriptive Notes: Dutch and English legends.
  References: Not in Norwich
  Norwich number: 1000
  RID: MOA 0147
  Africa -- Cape of Good Hope
- Allegorical source of Nile. Tzana or Lake of Dembea. -- Scherer, Heinrich, 1628-1704, No date; NOR 1001; : Uncolored; x
  Descriptive Notes: Dedication from Baines Barrington to James Bruce.
  Norwich number: 1001
  RID: MOA 0138
  Africa
- --, NOR 1002; :; x
  Descriptive Notes:
  Norwich number: 1002
  RID: MOA 0157
- Insula and Arx Mozambique. -- Bertius, Petrus, 1565-1629, 1618; NOR 1003; : Colored; x
  Norwich number: 1003
  RID: MOA 0001
  Africa -- Mozambique -- 17th c.
- Map of Libya. --: Basire (printer); Pors, Felicio, No date; NOR 1004; : Uncolored; x
  Descriptive Notes: Includes interior of North Egypt and Arabia.
  Norwich number: 1004
  RID: MOA 0002
- Sea chart of Simon's Bay. -- Belcher, Edward, Sir, 1799-1877 Sea chart, No date; NOR 1005; : Uncolored; x
  Norwich number: 1005
  RID: MOA 0132
  Africa -- Simon's Bay
- England to Cape of Good Hope. -- Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698 Sea chart, NOR 1006; :; x
  Descriptive Notes: East India emblem.
  Norwich number: 1006
  RID: MOA 0150
  Oceans -- Sea chart
- Carte des Isle de Cap-Verd. Plan de la Rade de la Praye. -- Paris Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780, 1774; NOR 1007; : Uncolored; x
  Norwich number: 1007
  RID: MOA 0131
- Africa. -- Stabilimento, Civelli Guiseppe, 1853; NOR 1008; :; x
  Norwich number: 1008
  RID: MOA 0261
- Azores. -- Ortelius, Abraham, 1527-1598, 1606; NOR 1009; : Colored; x
  Norwich number: 1009
  RID: MOA 0262
- Carte Generale de l'Afrique. -- Paris Beautemps-Beaupre, Charles Francois, 1766-1854, 1832; NOR 1010; :; x
  Norwich number: 1010
  RID: MOA 0263
- Suid-Afrika. = South Africa. -- Amsterdam De Bussey, NOR 1011; :; x
  Norwich number: 1011
  RID: MOA 0264
- Madagascar. -- Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780, 1775; NOR 1012; :; x
  Norwich number: 1012
  RID: MOA 0331
- Aethiopia. -- Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638, 1666; NOR 1013; :; x
  Descriptive Notes: Pres Joannis Imperium.
  Norwich number: 1013
  RID: MOA 0332
- Lake Tzana. -- Bruce, John, NOR 1014; :; x
  Norwich number: 1014
  RID: MOA 0333
- Carta particolare che comincia con il capo Dofar in Arabia e'finisce con il Capo Cincapora nell India. -- Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649, NOR 1015; :; x
  Norwich number: 1015
  RID: MOA 0334
- Carta particolare che comma con il Capo Baduis e finisce con il Capo Cumana. -- Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649, NOR 1016; :; x
  Norwich number: 1016
  RID: MOA 0335
- South Africa and Southern Indian Ocean. -- Norie, J.R., 1831; NOR 1017; :; x
  Norwich number: 1017
  RID: MOA 0336
- Engraving of Cape. -- Ogilby, John, 1600-1676, 1670; NOR 1018; :; x
  Norwich number: 1018
  RID: MOA 0338
- Islands in Atlantic and North African coast. -- Tallis, John, 1815 or 6-1876, NOR 1019; :; x
  Norwich number: 1019
  RID: MOA 0339
  Islands